Guide to the Donald Clifford Gallup Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Donald Clifford Gallup papers
1754-2000
1920-1995
YCAL MSS 838
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
93
(119 boxes) + 4 record album storage, 5 art
Correspondence, writings, research files, personal papers, photographs, printed material and other papers documenting both the professional and personal activities of Donald Gallup as scholarly bibliographer, editor, curator of the Yale Collection of American Literature, and book and manuscript collector on his own account. The majority of the collection consists of Gallup's own papers, including personal, professional and editorial correspondence; a small amount of personal papers; research files; and typescripts and galley proofs of many of his publications, including his editions of the journals of Thornton Wilder and several volumes of works by Eugene O'Neill. Correspondents include the authors James Purdy, Sheri Martinelli, and Mary Bernetta Quinn and the Yale librarian James T. Babb. In addition, the collection contains some of the letters and papers by Modernist writers collected by Gallup personally and donated by him to Yale. The most extensive of these groups is the collection of letters by T. S. Eliot in Group X. Recipients include Arnold Bennett, Richard Cobden-Sanderson, Edgar Jepson, Alida Monro and Harold Monro, Brigit Patmore, John Carroll Perkins, and Donald Gallup himself. Publishers' correspondence and book contracts of Carl Van Vechten are found in Group V., while Group VII. and Group VIII. contain copies of articles and ephemera by and related to Ezra Pound and a small amount of Pound correspondence. Diaries by Carlotta Monterey O'Neill are located in Group X.
Gallup, Donald, 1913-2000
Arrangement
Organized into twenty groupings: I. February 1992 Acquisition, 1958-1960. II. July 1986 Acquisition, 1985. III. March 1988 Acquisition, 1988. IV. February 1989 Acquisition, 1953. V. December 1989 Acquisition, 1904-1960. VI. October 1990 Acquisition, 1977-1979. VII. June 1991 Acquisition, 1916-1989. VIII. June 1992 Acquisition, 1909-1963. IX. August 1997 Acquisition, 1944-1976. X. February 2000 Acquisition, 1918-1964. XI. June 2000 Acquisition, 1912-1962. XII. July 2000 Acquisition, 1944-1999. XIII. July 2000 Acquisition, undated. XIV. April 2001 Acquisition, 1866-2000. XV. April 2001 Acquisition, 1754-1979. XVI. June 2001 Acquisition, 1947. XVII. September 2001 Acquisition, 1942. XVIII. May 2008 Acquisition, 1907-2000, XIX. May 2008 Acquisition, 1924-1933, undated. XX. February 1983 Acquisition, 1928- 1979.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 26, 113 - 115 (sound recordings and computer disk): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Donald Clifford Gallup (1913-2000)
Donald Clifford Gallup (Yale 1934), literary bibliographer, collector, and curator of the Yale Collection of American Literature for thirty years, was born in Sterling, Connecticut and received his B.A. and Ph.D. in English from Yale University. With the exception of a few years at Southern Methodist University and service in the Army during World War II, Gallup spent his entire career at Yale, first as librarian and then as curator of the Yale Collection of American Literature. In that role he was primarily responsible for building Yale's American Modernist collections, acquiring the archives of Mabel Dodge Luhan, Ezra Pound, H.D., Gertrude Stein, Eugene O'Neill, William Carlos Williams, Josephine Herbst, Mina Loy, and Thornton Wilder. Gallup published full bibliographies of T.S. Eliot (1952) and Ezra Pound (1963), as well as numerous editions of works by the authors whose papers he collected. After his retirement from Yale in 1984, he authored two memoirs: Pigeons on the Granite (1988) and What Mad Pursuits (1998). He died in Branford, Connecticut in September 2000 and bequeathed his papers to the Yale Collection of American Literature.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, writings, research files, personal papers, photographs, printed material and other papers documenting both the professional and personal activities of Donald Gallup as scholarly bibliographer, editor, curator of the Yale Collection of American Literature, and book and manuscript collector on his own account. The majority of the collection consists of Gallup's own papers, including personal, professional and editorial correspondence; a small amount of personal papers; research files; and typescripts and galley proofs of many of his publications, including his editions of the journals of Thornton Wilder and several volumes of works by Eugene O'Neill. Correspondents include the authors James Purdy, Sheri Martinelli, and Mary Bernetta Quinn and the Yale librarian James T. Babb. In addition, the collection contains some of the letters and papers by Modernist writers collected by Gallup personally and donated by him to Yale. The most extensive of these groups is the collection of letters by T. S. Eliot in Group X. Recipients include Arnold Bennett, Richard Cobden-Sanderson, Edgar Jepson, Alida Monro and Harold Monro, Brigit Patmore, John Carroll Perkins, and Donald Gallup himself. Publishers' correspondence and book contracts of Carl Van Vechten are found in Group V., while Group VII. and Group VIII. contain copies of articles and ephemera by and related to Ezra Pound and a small amount of Pound correspondence. Diaries by Carlotta Monterey O'Neill are located in Group X.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift and bequest of Donald Clifford Gallup, 1982-2008.
American drama -- 20th Century; American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Authors and publishers -- United States; Collectors and collecting; Librarians -- United States; Manuscripts -- Collectors and collecting; Modernism (Literature); Publishers and publishing -- United States; Scholars -- United States; Audiovisual material -- United States -- 20th Century; Born digital -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Book collectors -- United States -- 20th Century; Librarians -- United States -- 20th Century; Babb, James T. (James Tinkham), 1899-1968; Bennett, Arnold, 1867-1931; Cobden-Sanderson, Richard; Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965; Friede, Donald; Gallup, Donald, 1913-2000; Jepson, Edgar, 1863-1938; Martinelli, Sheri; Monro, Alida Klemantaski; Monro, Harold, 1879-1932; O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986; O'Neill, Carlotta; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953; Patmore, Brigit; Perkins, John Carroll, 1862-1950; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972; Purdy, James, 1914-2009; Quinn, Mary Bernetta, 1915-; Stein, Gertrude, 1874-1946; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975; Yale University -- Employees
- February 1982 Acquisition, 1958-1960; 1; 1.84; (6 boxes)
  Arrangement
  This material is organized under two headings: Correspondence and Writings.
  Scope and Contents
  The February 1982 Acquisition contains correspondence of Donald C.Gallup as well as transcripts, photocopies, and photostats of correspondence and writings of Eugene O'Neill. Writings are typescript drafts and first proofs of O'Neill publications, edited by Donald C. Gallup, including Inscriptions, Poems, 1912-1942, Work Diary, 1924-1943, and "The Last Will and Testament of Silverdene Emblem O'Neill." Writings also include first proofs of Donald Gallup's article "Eugene O'Neill's 'The Ancient Mariner'."
  - Correspondence
    - Cole, Edward C., 1958 (Box 1)
    - Lax, Stephen, 1958 April 21 (Box 1)
  - Writings
    - Gallup, Donald C.
      - "Eugene O'Neill's 'The Ancient Mariner'", undated; 3 (Box 5 (Oversize))
    - O'Neill, Eugene
      - Inscriptions: Eugene O'Neill to Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, 1960, undated; 15 (Box 1)
        Includes reproductions and transcripts, drafts, and setting copies.
      - Inscriptions: Eugene O'Neill to Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, 1958-1960; 5 (Box 2)
      - "The Last Will and Testament of Silverdene Emblem O'Neill", undated (Box 5 (Oversize))
      - "More Stately Mansions", undated; 7 (Box 2)
      - Poems 1912-1942, undated; 6 (Box 2)
      - Poems 1912-1942, undated; 8 (Box 3)
      - Work Diary; transcribed by Donald Gallup, undated; 4 (Box 4)
  - Oversize Material
    - O'Neill, Eugene. Inscriptions: Eugene O'Neill to Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, 1958 (Box 5 (Oversize))
    - Gallup, Donald C. "Eugene O'Neill The Ancient Mariner", undated; 3 (Box 5 (Oversize))
    - O'Neill, Eugene. "The Last Will and Testament of Silverdene Emblem O'Neill", undated (Box 5 (Oversize))
    - O'Neill, Eugene. "More Stately Mansions", undated (Box 6 (Oversize))
    - O'Neill, Eugene. Inscriptions: Eugene O'Neill to Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, undated (Box 6 (Oversize))
- July 1986 Acquisition, 1985; 2; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  The July 1986 Acquisition contains proofs and setting typescripts of The Journals of Thornton Wilder, 1939-1961 selected and edited by Donald Gallup.
  - The Journals of Thornton Wilder, 1939-1961, 1985; 2 (Box 7)
  - The Journals of Thornton Wilder, 1939-1961, undated; 5 (Box 8)
- March 1988 Acquisition, 3; 0.25; (1 box)
  The March 1988 Acquisition contains a typescript of Donald Gallup's interviews with Georgia O'Keeffe.
  - "Conversations with Georgia O'Keeffe, Ghost Ranch and Abiquiu, New Mexico, 1965-1983, as recorded by Donald Gallup", 1988 March 24 (Box 9)
- February 1989 Acquisition, 1953; 4; 0.21; (1 box)
  The February 1989 Acquisition contains the original typescript of Flowers of Friendship: Letters Written to Gertrude Stein, selected and edited by Donald Gallup, from which the setting typescript was prepared and corrected.
  - The Flowers of Friendship: Letters Written to Gertrude Stein, 1953; 4 (Box 10)
- December 1989 Acquisition, 1904-1960; 5; 0.42; (1 box) (Box 11)
  Arranged alphabetically.
  The December 1989 Acquisition contains contracts, copyright regulations, and correspondence.
  - The Blind Bow-Boy; Carl Van Vechten, 1922-1950 (Box 11)
  - Covarrubias & Alastair, 1925 March 7 (Box 11)
  - Excavations; Carl Van Vechten, 1925-1953 (Box 11)
  - Feathers; Carl Van Vechten, 1930-1957 (Box 11)
  - Firbank, Ronald. Prancing Nigger, 1924 January 19 (Box 11)
  - Firecrackers; Carl Van Vechten, 1923-1952 (Box 11)
  - "Five Old English Ditties"; Carl Van Vechten, 1904 December (Box 11)
  - Fragments From an Unwritten Autobiography; Carl Van Vechten, 1956 January 13 (Box 11)
  - In the Garret; Carl Van Vechten, 1919-1947 (Box 11)
  - Interpreters; Carl Van Vechten, 1917-1947 (Box 11)
  - Lords of the House Tops; Carl Van Vechten, 1920-1948 (Box 11)
  - The Merry-Go-Round; Carl Van Vechten, 1918-1945 (Box 11)
  - Music After the Great War, and Other Studies; Carl Van Vechten, 1915-1953 (Box 11)
  - Music and Bad Manners; Carl Van Vechten, 1916-1944 (Box 11)
  - Music of Spain; Carl Van Vechten, 1918-1945 (Box 11)
  - Nigger Heaven; Carl Van Vechten, 1926-1953 (Box 11)
  - "Notes For an Autobiography", 1936 September 2 (Box 11)
  - Ouida. In the Winter of Cities, 1923 March 22 (Box 11)
  - Parties; Carl Van Vechten, 1930 (Box 11)
  - Peter Whiffle: His Life and Works; Carl Van Vechten, 1927-1954 (Box 11)
  - Red; Carl Van Vechten, 1924-1952 (Box 11)
  - Sacred and Profane Memories; Carl Van Vechten, 1936-1960 (Box 11)
  - Shiel, M. P. The Lord of the Sea, 1924 June 3 (Box 11)
  - Spider Boy; Carl Van Vechten, 1928-1955 (Box 11)
  - Stein, Gertrude. Four Saints, 1934 February 2 (Box 11)
  - Stein, Gertrude. Three Lives, 1933 July 11 (Box 11)
  - The Tatooed Countess; Carl Van Vechten, 1924-1951; 3 (Box 11)
  - The Tiger in the House; Carl Van Vechten, 1920-1960 (Box 11)
  - Copyright, 1929-1944 (Box 11)
- October 1990 Acquisition, 1977-1979; 6; 0.42; (1 box)
  The October 1990 Acquisition contains proofs with corrections by Donald Gallup, and the setting copy with publisher's editorial markings of Thornton Wilder's plays "The Alcestiad" and "The Drunken Sisters," published by Harper & Row.
  - Thornton, Wilder. The Alcestiad, 1977-1979; 4 (Box 12)
- June 1991 Acquisition, 1916-1989; 7; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  The June 1991 Acquisition contains photocopies, photostats, and transcripts of articles and reviews as well as printed ephemera by or relating to Ezra Pound.
  - Pound, Ezra
    - "Le Major C.-H. Douglas et la situation en Angleterre." Les Écrits Nouveaux, 1921 August / September (Box 13)
    - "Démocratie économique"; "Prose anglaise contemporaine"; Un petit guide pour l'étranger bien intentionné." L'Art Libre, 1920
    - "Due volte crocifisso." La Prima, 1960 July / August
    - "Un inédit d'Ezra Pound." Combat, 1967 July 18
    - "Vorticismo." Il Mare, Supplemento Letterario, 1933 February 18
    - Carta a C. J. C., 1960
    - "Marches Civilization." Chicago Tribune. Italian Supplement, 1933
    - "Assassinio", undated
    - "Presenza di F. T. Marinetti"; "Canto LXXIII." La Marina Republicana, undated
    - "Culture as (Unusually) Usual." Town & Country, 1940 December
    - "Il giudizio di uno straniero." Antieuropa, 1939 November / December
    - "Death of Yeats End of Irish Literary Revival, Says Pound, Noh Enthusiast." Japan Time & Mail, 1939 June 5
    - Contributions to The New English Weekly, Broletto, The Courier, and The Open Road, undated
    - "Mr. Eliot's Solid Merit." The New English Weekly, 1934 July 12
    - "A Problem of (Specifically) Style." The Harvard Advocate, 1935
    - Contributions to Il Mare, Supplemento Letterario, 1933
    - "Mr. Ezra Pound and the Press", undated
    - Contributions to L'Indice, 1930
    - Scrapbook with newspaper clippings, 1929, undated
    - "Two Unpublished Poems by Ezra Pound." The New York Times Book Review, 1988 January 10
    - "Letters to William Butler Yeats." Antaeus, 1976 Spring / Summer
    - "Ezra Pound's Letters to an Editor of His Anthology." Kwartalnik Neofilologiczny, 1973
    - "Ezra Pound's Letters to a Polish Scholar." Kwartalnik Neofilologiczny, 1979
    - "From: CXII." Agenda, 1963/1964
    - "Canto 120." New York Times Book Review, 1972 November 26
    - Newspaper clipping of letter to the editor of The Richmond News Leader, 1959 July 14
    - Excerpts from Pound's broadcasts. Carolina Quarterly, 1959 Winter
    - Published letters to the editor of The Saturday Review, 1927-1944
    - "The Passport Nuisance." The New York Herald, 1924 November 19
      Includes quotes from Pound's letters to the editor of The Publisher's Weekly.
    - Letter to the editor of The New York Herald relating to "The Passport Nuisance", undated (Box 14)
    - "The Mourn of Life", undated
    - "Part of Canto XX." The Exile, undated
    - "A Communication from Ezra Pound", 1924
    - "Drunken Helots and Mr. Eliot." The Egoist, 1917 June
    - Brief review relating to Raymonde Collignon, undated
    - "Henry James - The Last Phase." Newark Sunday Call, undated
    - Published letters to editors, undated
    - "Credit and the Fine Arts." The New Age, 1922 March 30
    - "James Joyce and Pecuchet", undated
    - "Dialogues of Fontanelle"; translated by Ezra Pound. The Egoist, 1916 July 1
    - "Extracts from Press Notices of A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man by James Joyce", undated
    - "Gather the Limbs of Odin." The New Age, 1911 December 28
    - "Certain Poems of Kabir"; translated by Kali Mohan Ghose and Ezra Pound. The Modern Review, 1913 June
    - "Ikon." Cerebralist, 1913 December
    - "Extracts from Press Notices of Dubliners by James Joyce", undated
    - "Extracts from Press Notices of Exiles by James Joyce", undated
    - "Christmas Prologue." The Sunday School Times, undated
  - Arts Club of Chicago. An Exhibition of Sculpture by Brancusi, 1927
    Includes excerpt by Ezra Pound.
  - Anceschi, Luciano. "Ezra Pound y el humanismo poetico americano", undated
  - Anceschi, Luciano. "Palinsesti del protoumanesimo poetico americano", 1950
  - "En el LXXIII cumpleaños de Ezra Pound." Excelsiór, 1959 March 29
  - "Clarifications"; reprinted from New Times, 1955 September 23
  - Notes relating to "Strike", undated
  - "Ecrire franchement ce qu'ils pensent", undated
  - Bornstein, George. "Eight Letters From Ezra Pound to Parker Tyler in the 1930s", undated
  - Slocum, John J. "Remembering Ezra Pound." The Yale University Library Gazette, 1952 October
  - Oldani, Louis. "Two Unpublished Pound Letters: Pound's Aid to Dreiser", 1977 Summer
  - Lanciotti, Lionello. "Un carteggio inedito di Ezra Pound", 1981
  - Hungville, Maurice. "Ezra Pound, Educator: Two Uncollected Pound Letters." Reprinted from American Literature, 1972 November
  - Tanselle, Thomas G. "Two Early Letters of Ezra Pound." Reprinted from American Literature, 1962 March
  - Empty envelope addressed to Donald Gallup with handwritten notes, 1960
  - Schneeman, Peter. "Pound's "Englischer Brief": A Look Toward Germany." Paideuma, 1978
  - Lewis, P. Wyndham. "Extracts From Press Notices of Tarr", undated
  - Bird, William. "Did Beautiful Authoress Tip the Scales of Justice in Favor of Ezra Pound, American Poet? Knoxville Sentinel, 1923 November 25
  - Letter to the editor of The New York Herald relating to "Arithmetic and Music", undated
  - Morton, Frank. "Mr. Ezra Pound and Vorticism." The Triad, 1915 March 10
  - "News and Gossip of the Literary World." Boston Evening Transcript, 1915 July 14
  - Review by Ella Wheeler Wilcox. American Journal Examiner, 1908 December 14
  - Correspondence between Donald Gallup and Mary L. Elder, 1973
    Includes photocopy of newspaper clipping.
- June 1992 Acquisition, 1909-1963; 8; 0.5; (2 boxes)
  The June 1992 Acquisition contains chiefly correspondence of Ezra Pound and Donald S. Friede most of which was acquired by Donald C. Gallup from various booksellers.
  - Correspondence of Ezra Pound
    - Bennett, Arnold, 1919 January 20 (Box 15)
    - Brodzky, Horace, 1915, undated
    - Buss, Kate, 1922-1923; 2
    - Carter, Huntly, 1917, undated
    - Chapman, Dodd, 1922, undated
    - Chapman, Guy, 1922-1923
    - Chute, Desmond, 1936 February 1
    - Friede, Donald, 1927
    - Gallup, Donald, 1958-1959
    - Gingrich, Arthur, 1934
    - Harding, E. A. F., 1932
    - Jepson, Edgar, 1909-1918
    - Laughlin, James, 1947, 1963
    - Mariotti, Raymond B., 1932 May 16
    - Mathews, Elkin, 1909-1916
    - Paquette, David J., 1949-1950, undated
    - Pinker, J. B., 1915 July 3
    - Schwartz, Jacob, 1930
    - Sharpe, L. Geoffrey, 1937
    - Swabey, Henry, 1951, undated
    - Taylor, Rachel Annand, 1911-1915
    - Verschoyle, Derek, 1933
    - Wykes-Joyce, Max, 1950 October 27
  - Correspondence of Donald S. Friede with or in regards to George Antheil, 1927; 3
  - "Five Troubadour Songs," English words adapted from Chaucer, music arranged by Agnes Bedford; plate proofs, 1920 October 3; 2 (Box 16)
    Includes manila envelope addressed to Donald C. Gallup.
- August 1997 Acquisition, 1944-1976; 9; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  The August 1997 Acquisition contains correspondence, printed material, a photograph, writings, notes, curator's files and research files by or relating to Donald Gallup and Gertrude Stein. The correspondence of Donald Gallup consists of professional letters from The New Republic, Liveright, and others regarding the publication of Gertrude Stein's Fernhurst, Q.E.D. and Other Early Writings. The correspondence of Gertrude Stein and Alice B. Toklas contains transcripts of personal letters to friends and family members. The Writings consist chiefly of advance proofs of Flowers of Friendship: Letters Written to Gertrude Stein, edited by Donald Gallup; setting typescript and galley proofs of as well as correspondence relating to Fernhurst, Q.E.D. and Other Early Writings by Gertrude Stein; proofs of Four in America by Gertrude Stein. Other Papers contain newspaper clippings, printed material and card catalogs.
  Organized under four headings: Correspondence of Donald C. Gallup, Correspondence of Gertrude Stein and Alice B. Toklas, Writings, and Other Papers.
  - Correspondence of Donald C. Gallup
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1970-1975, undated; 2 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence of Gertrude Stein and Alice B. Toklas
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
    - Breon, John, undated
    - Breon, Jessie P. Rockford, undated
    - Cerf, Bennett, undated
    - Cocteau, Jean, undated
    - Goodspeed, Charles, undated
    - Haas, Robert Bartlett, undated
    - Hubbell, Lindley, undated
    - Jacob, Max, undated
    - Johnson, Lamont, Mrs. & Mrs. Robert Clairborne, undated
    - Lynes, George Platt, undated
    - McBride, Henry, undated
    - Richards, Grant, undated
    - Rönnebeck, Arnold, undated
    - Rogers, W. G., undated
    - Stein, Julian, Mrs., undated
      Includes only typed transcripts of letters.
    - Tanner, Allen & Pavel Tchelitchew, undated
    - Thomson, Virgil, undated
    - Weeks, Mabel Foote, undated
    - White, Max, undated
    - Wendell, Wilcox, undated
    - Woojums, Papa, undated
    - Young, Mahonri M., undated
  - Writings
    - Breon, John. "A Novel or a Play", undated (Box 18)
    - Coates, Robert. "Yesterday's Burdens", undated
    - Stein, Gertrude
      - Article, 1975
      - "The Atomic Bomb", undated
      - Bee Time Vine, undated
        Includes dust jackets.
      - Blood on the Dining-Room Floor, undated
      - Fernhurst, Q.E.D. and Other Early Writings, undated; 2
      - Four in America, undated; 2 (Box 19)
      - "How Could They Marry Her", 1947-1964
      - "Rich and Poor in English", undated
      - The World is Round, 1965-1966, undated; 4
      - "Yes Is For a Very Young Man", undated
    - Unsorted writings, undated; 7 (Box 20)
  - Other Papers
    - Newspaper clippings, correspondence, and printed ephemera, 1975-1976, undated
    - Arrivals in the ABC Berg Collection, undated
    - Newspaper clippings, exhibition announcements and brochures, circa 1956-1959
    - "A Tribute to Ezra Pound", undated
      Includes newspaper clippings and other printed ephemera.
    - Printed material, 1944, undated
    - Catalog cards and handwritten notes, undated; 4
- February 2000 Acquisition, 1918-1964; 10; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  The February 2000 Acquisition consists of writings by T.S. Eliot, transcripts of BBC talks, and correspondence. The manuscripts contain setting typescripts and proofs of T.S. Eliot's writings, including The Use of Poetry and the Use of Criticism. BBC Talks consist of typescripts of T. S. Eliot's radio talks on British and European Literature. Correspondence includes letters, Christmas cards, and other ephemera by T. S. Eliot, collected by Donald Gallup. Additionally, the series includes letters from T. S. Eliot to Donald Gallup, Arnold Bennett, R. Cobden-Sanderson, Harold Monro and others.
  Organized under three headings: Manuscripts, BBC Talks, and Correspondence.
  - T. S. Eliot Papers
    - Manuscripts
      - "The Anniversary", 1935 June 6 (Box 21)
        Immediate Source of Acquisition
        Purchased Goodspeed's 1972
        Typescript (original) signed: 1 leaf, 25 1/2cm.
        A 20-line rhymed toast to Dr. John Carroll Perkins, inscribed: "In memoriam June 6th, 1935."
      - "Ash-Wednesday", undated
        Sheets for text set in quarto as originally planned: 7 leaves and 1 blank leaf [A]-[B]4 (B4 blank). 28 1/2cm. (8 L.)
        (Listed also as item 85a in catalogue of "T. S. Eliot Collection" books.)
      - "The Cocktail Party", 1949, undated; 2
        Purchased Horowitz, 14 March 1990.
        Acting script, reproduced from typewritten copy, New York, Richard Madden Co.; 3 leaves, 47 numbered leaves, 1 leaf, 44 numbered leaves. 28cm.
        With manuscript additions and changes in an unidentified hand. In folding box.
      - The Confidential Clerk, undated
        Purchased House of Books Ltd., 1967.
        Mimeograph script. London, Henry Sherek Ltd. 2 leaves, 30, 30, 35 numbered leaves. 25 1/2cm.